

Charlie Gunning

chas90@gmail.com | +44 (0) 7904 475365

PERSONAL

I am a self-driven individual with over 6 years of development experience, leading development on multiple key business projects throughout my career. I have a logical mind with a practical approach to problem-solving and a drive to see deliverables through to completion. I am a quick learner. I specialise in T-SQL, but also self-develop my knowledge outside of work. I have experience using many different languages, including C, C#, HTML, JavaScript, Python and VBA.

EDUCATION, TRAINING & ACHIEVEMENTS

HARVARD (HARVARDX)

Jun 2021 – Present

CS50's Introduction to Computer Science

MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (MITX)

Jan 2019 – Mar 2019

6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python

Pass (98%)

INTERNATIONAL SOFTWARE TESTING QUALIFICATIONS BOARD (ISTQB)

Nov 2017 - Nov 2017

ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level

Pass

WESTCLIFF HIGH SCHOOL FOR BOYS (SIXTH FORM COLLEGE)

Sep 2001 – Sep 2008

A-Level Geology B AS-Level Chemistry B
A-Level Physics C AS-Level Mathematics D

10 x GCSE A* - C

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Weekly awards for taking ownership, great communication and supporting other teams in the business.
- Quarterly awards for actively seeking cross-skilling opportunities, instilling a one-team ethos, and supporting other teams by leading Excel training sessions
- Annual awards for quickly becoming a valued member of the team and taking ownership with self-development and seeking out opportunities to encourage improvements within the team.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BARCLAYS PLC Apr 2021 - Present

SQL Developer

- Co-leading design, implementation and maintenance of the business's project and resource management tool.
- Lead developer on relational database design and future considerations for the above platform.
- Lead developer on merging and reconciliation of data from multiple resource systems.
- Lead developer on migrating the platform from a VBA front-end to a web-based front-end.
- Leading integration of a Version Control System into the team's processes.
- Communicating change and building relationships with key stakeholders throughout the business.
- Maintaining and prioritising work backlog items.
- Supporting the above by using tools and languages, including:
 - o T-SQL (DDL, DML, TCL, DQL, tables, views, stored procedures, functions)
 - SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS ETL/ELT)
 - o Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code
 - o Git, Bitbucket
 - o Excel, VBA
 - o HTML, CSS, JavaScript

SQL Developer

- Co-leading design, implementation and maintenance of the business's healthcare data platform.
- Supporting the above by using tools and software, including Tableau, Git, GitHub and Visual Studio Code.
- Sole developer on producing a new user management desktop application (using Electron, Chromium, Node.js, HTML/CSS/JavaScript) receiving positive feedback from the business and reducing manual overhead considerably.
- Processing and anonymising sensitive healthcare information, including data from NHS Digital.

SKIPTON BUILDING SOCIETY

Sep 2015 - Apr 2019

Business Intelligence (BI) Specialist

- Designing, implementing, and maintaining the business's Operational Data Store (ODS) and Data Warehouse (DW).
- Creating and maintaining SSIS packages to aid with the above process.
- Promoting code through different environments (i.e. Test/UAT/Pre-Production/Production) through Source Control.
- Performing systems testing on solutions and reporting defects through ticketing system (TFS 2012).
- Extensive use of SSMS to create/alter tables/procedures as well as querying the ODS/DW for analysis and reporting.
- Building reporting solutions using SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS), Report Builder, SharePoint lists and Excel.
- Consistently being recognised for the above responsibilities and extra work through weekly, monthly, quarterly, and annual awards within the department.

SKIPTON BUILDING SOCIETY

Mar 2015 - Sep 2015

Customer Adviser

TRUSTFORD WILMSLOW

Sep 2014 - Feb 2015

Used Car Sales Executive

LADBROKES PLC

Jul 2008 - Aug 2014

Customer Service Manager

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

GREATER MANCHESTER POLICE – OLDHAM DIVISION

Mar 2011 - Sep 2012

Special Constable

- Same responsibilities and powers as with regular Police Officer duties.
- Patrolling the local area to create visible presence as well as deter or handle criminal activity.
- Attending local events to ensure public safety and offer support.
- Involvement in organised operations to act against drug-related criminal activity.
- Working with Response Officers to respond to '999' emergencies.

HOBBIES, INTERESTS & REFERENCES

HOBBIES & INTERESTS











Gaming

Driving

Riding

avelling

Languages

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.